<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOTAS on Ventorvar Gaming</title>
    <link>https://ventorvar.com/tags/hotas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HOTAS on Ventorvar Gaming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright> </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ventorvar.com/tags/hotas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Advanced Joystick Configs - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://ventorvar.com/posts/joystick-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ventorvar.com/posts/joystick-intro/</guid>
      <description>Just need the configs? For SC head to TL;DR
A note on the update: If you followed the previous version of this guide, you no longer need HidGuardian! Also Joystick Gremlin no longer needs to run as an administrator.
The Problem We&amp;rsquo;re Trying to Solve Using multiple joysticks on Windows can be a huge pain. There is no guarantee of the input device order when your machine reboots or when they&amp;rsquo;re plugged, even if you follow the same order every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Advanced Joystick Configs - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ventorvar.com/posts/joystick-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ventorvar.com/posts/joystick-config/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is part 2 of a series. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already installed all the required tools, go check out part 1 first.
Just need the configs? go to the TL;DR
Getting familiar with Joystick Gremlin The keystone to our entire setup is Joystick Gremlin (JG). JG allows you to remap inputs from your devices to other inputs on your system. For example, you can configure it so with you press the trigger button on your left joystick, it presses the Shift key on your keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TL;DR - Advanced Joystick Configs for Star Citizen </title>
      <link>https://ventorvar.com/posts/joystick-sc-tldr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ventorvar.com/posts/joystick-sc-tldr/</guid>
      <description>Star Citizen Advanced Controls Configuration These configurations are based off my personal setup for Star Citizen and are outlined in a two part guide on this site. That being said there are a few requirements, and you can use my configurations as a starting point whether or not you have the same joystick setup.
Note: This was last updated for Star Citizen 3.17.2-PTU.8143480 and may or may not work with the current build</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>devreorder Setup Guide</title>
      <link>https://ventorvar.com/posts/devreorder-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ventorvar.com/posts/devreorder-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Note: This was a previous method for controlling how games see your input devices. This is no longer used in the primary guide but is kept here for reference.
dinput8 DLL wrapper called devreorder
Setting up devreorder Note: If devreorder doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with your game, HidGuardian is another option to hide inputs from your game
Download the latest release here (the zip file) Unzip x64/dinput8.dll to your Star Citizen LIVE\Bin64 folder next to StarCitizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HidGuardian Setup Guide</title>
      <link>https://ventorvar.com/posts/hidguardian-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ventorvar.com/posts/hidguardian-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re playing a game that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work with devreorder, HidGuardian is another options to filter your inputs.
Setting up HidGuardian Note: If HidGuardian does not work well on your system, there is a work around for Star Citizen at least. SC will only see devices that are present when it is launched. Therefore, you can launch SC, then attach your devices. You&amp;rsquo;ll still have to make sure they are loaded correctly in JG, however</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gladiator K from VKB</title>
      <link>https://ventorvar.com/posts/gladiator-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ventorvar.com/posts/gladiator-k/</guid>
      <description>Star Citizen Advanced Controls Configuration </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
